American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection 1960-present Mss.497.3.Am4
American Philosophical Society
Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection
1960-present
Mss.497.3.Am4
American Philosophical Society
30.0 Linear feet
The Phillips Fund Collection consists of materials submitted to the APS by recipients of grants from its Phillips Fund for Native American Research. The materials vary in scope, ranging from linguistics to ethnography, musicology, religion, ethnobotany, and history, and including study of Indian cultures from Canada, the United States, and Mexico.
American Philosophical Society.
General note
Information for applicants for Phillips Fund grants is located on the APS website at http://www.amphilsoc.org/grants/phillips.
Related Archival Materials note
Materials submitted by some Phillips Fund grantees may be located in:
American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American Languages Collections. (Mss.497.3.B63c).
Separated Materials note
Audio and video recordings are housed with the audiovisual collections, and are inventoried separately.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of grantees.
Scope and Contents note
The Phillips Fund Collection contains material submitted to the American Philosophical Society by grantees of the Phillips Fund for Native American Research. The subdisciplines represented and the subject matter are highly varied, but include project reports, dissertations, published and unpublished papers, dictionaries and vocabularies, field notes, and audiovisual materials.
While no systematic effort was made to gather the results of early Phillips grants, several grantees, including Zellig Harris, sent sound recordings, notes, or other works anyway. In most cases, these were incorporated into the American Council of Learned Society's Committee on Native American Languages Collection (also known as the Franz Boas Linguistic Collection).
Native American Images note: Over 400 black and white silver gelatin photographs, color photographs, color slides, color VHS video, photocopy prints, and ink sketches of eleven different Native American tribes contained in thirteen grantee reports from 1964-1995. Arranged alphabetically by contributor, the images reflect Seneca political charts (Abler); Mayan street festivals (Adams); early Minnesota Dakota settlements (Bray); old Oraibi Hopi pueblo (Cameron); murals of Oklahoma tribes (Carlisle); Taino island scenes (Forbes); Navajo mountain community (Hammond); Conquest of Itza (Hellmuth); Hopi pottery (Kealiinohomoku); Stockbridge-Munsee community (Mochon); Dakota Pine Ridge reservation (Powers); Mixtec picture-writing (Troike); Seneca dwellings (Wyler). Of note, the Oklahoma post office murals of Seminoles, Kiowa, and Chickasaws were painted by Native American artists from 1939-1943. Also of note, the Bray video details cartographer Joseph Nicollet 1836-1840 expedition to the Upper Mississippi River. Most of the grants are referenced in Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian. The slides by Powers are housed in the Photograph Collection; the photographs by Mochon are in the Speck Collection (572.97 Sp3, Box 10, folders 22-23). All other images are housed with their corresponding textual reports.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1895, Henry Phillips left a portion of his estate to the American Philosophical Society to support research in archaeology and philology, to which supplementary bequests were added in 1903 by his aunt, Emily Phillips, and uncle, Henry M. Phillips. Originally used to acquire books in these subject areas, the increasing strength of the APS collections for Native American languages combined with a critical need for support for primary research led to a gradual change in the use of the Phillips Fund.
Since the 1930s, the APS had provided grants to support research on Native American languages, but in 1941, a Special Committee on the Future Policy of the Library recommended tapping the Phillips Fund for this purpose. Following approval of the Committee on the Library in 1944, the first grant under the Phillips Fund was awarded in the fall, 1945, supporting Zellig Harris of the University of Pennsylvania in his research on the Cherokee language. Since the 1960s, the results of Phillips grants -- including field notes, audio and visual recordings, dissertations, and published and unpublished works -- have been sent to the Library for inclusion in its collections.
The Phillips Fund currently provides grants for research in Native American linguistics and ethnohistory, and the history of studies of Native Americans, in the continental United States and Canada. Grants are not made for projects in archaeology, ethnography, psycholinguistics, or for the preparation of pedagogical materials.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Nicollet, J.N. (Joseph Nicolas), 1786-1843; Occom, Samson, 1723-1792; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941; Acoma language; Anthropology--History; Arapaho Indians--Music; Arapaho language; Athapascan Indians; Athapascan languages; Cahuilla language; Carrier language; Cherokee Indians; Cherokee Indians--History; Cherokee language; Cheyenne Indians; Cheyenne language; Chickasaw Indians; Chilcotin language; Choctaw Indians; Choctaw language; Cochiti dialect; Columbia-Wenatchi language; Comox language; Cree language; Creek Indians; Creek Indians--History; Creek language; Dakota Indians; Dakota Indians--History; Dakota Indians--Music; Dakota language; Delaware Indians--Music; Diegueno language; Dogrib Indians; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Eskimo languages; Eskimos; Ethnobotany; Field notes.; Fox language; Fur trade; Gelatin silver prints; Gwenhoot Indians; Haida Indians; Haida language; Haisla Indians; Hare Indians; Heiltsuk Indians--History; Hidatsa Indians; Hidatsa language; Highland Chontal language; Hopi dance; Hopi Indians--History; Hopi language; Hualapai language; Hupa language; Indians of Mexico; Indians of Mexico--Mexico--Chiapas; Indians of Mexico--Oaxaca; Indians of Mexico--Religion; Indians of North America; Indians of North America--Alaska; Indians of North America--Arizona; Indians of North America--Arkansas; Indians of North America--Canada; Indians of North America--Michigan; Indians of North America--Minnesota; Indians of North America--Missions; Indians of North America--New York (State); Indians of North America--Oklahoma; Indians of North America--South Dakota; Indians of North America--Wisconsin; Indians of the West Indies--Antilles, Lesser; Iowa language; Iroquois Indians--History; Iroquois Indians--Virginia; Jemez language; Karok language; Kawki language; Kiowa Indians; Koasati language; Kutenai language; Lacandon Indians; Little Bog Horn, Battle of, 1876; Mam language; Mandan Indians; Mandan language; Massachusett language; Matlatzinca language; Maya Indians; Mayan languages; Mazatec language; Menominee language; Michif language; Micmac Indians; Miwok language; Mixtec Indians; Mobilian trade language; Mohawk Indians; Mohawk Indians--History; Mohawk language; Munsee Indians--History; Nahuatl language; Narragansett Indians--History; Navajo Indians--History; Navajo language; Nez Perce Indians--History; Nez Percé language; Niska language; Nootka language; Ntlakyapamuk Indians; Ntlakyapamuk language; Ojibwa Indians; Ojibwa Indians--History; Ojibwa language; Okanagan language; Oneida language; Onondaga language; Otomi language; Ottawa Indians--History; Paiute language; Papamiento language; Passamaquoddy Indians; Passamaquoddy language; Pawnee Indians; Penobscot Indians--History; Penobscot language; Photographs; Photomechanical prints; Pima Bajo language; Pima language; Plains Indians; Pokomam language; Pomo language; Potawatomi language; Powhattan Indians--History; Pueblo Indians; Quileute language; Salishan languages; Sandia dialect; Seminole Indians; Seminole Indians--History; Seneca Indians--History; Seneca language; Shawnee language; Siksika Indians; Siouan languages; Sketches.; Slides.; Smallpox; Sound recordings; Southwest Indians; Spokane language; Stockbridge Indians--History; Tahltan language; Taino Indians; Teton Indians--History; Tlakluit language; Tlingit Indians; Tohono O'Odham dialect; Tolowa language; Tsimshian Indians; Tsimshian language; Tuscarora Indians--History; Wakashan language; Wasco language; Western Apache language; Wichita language; Xinca language; Yakama language; Yamasee War, 1715; Yana language; Yavapai language; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi language; Yuma language; Yupik languages; Zapotec language; Zuni Indians--History; Zuni language
- American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection (Box 1-30)
  - Political Ethnohistory of the Seneca Nation, 1966; Abler, Thomas S.
    Scope and Contents note
    Report (1p.); 2 papers: "The political history of the Seneca Nations..." and "Factional dispute and party conflict in the political system of the Seneca nation (1845-1895)" Images include photmechanical prints of Senecas in New York State, their councils, community buildings, anf flow chart of political system.
    (Freeman guide 4709)
  - Report; [Colville Reservation/ Washington State]; [Extended family structure/ Plateau Indians], 1982; Ackerman, Lillian A.
    Transcripts of life history interviews with Sophie Gabourie, Sept. 18, 1979 (38p.); and Isabel Arcasa Oct. 2, 1979 (35p.); Rec. 119
  - Adams, Walter Randolph
    Native American Images note
    Black and white, color photographs, ink sketches of mayan processions, festivals, dances, masks.
    - "Religious, archaeological, and ethnohistorical...", 1977; Adams, Walter Randolph
      - Mayan celebration, 1977; Adams, Walter Randolph
      - Mayan celebration, 1977; Adams, Walter Randolph
      - Mayan diablito, 1977; Adams, Walter Randolph
    - "Field Notes...", 1978; Adams, Walter Randolph
    - "Religious practices of southeastern Chiapas, Mexico", 1977; Adams, Walter Randolph
    - "Pilgrimages and politico-economic organization: the Tzeltal-Tojolabal pilgrimages of southeastern Chiapas; n. d", 1981; Adams, Walter Randolph
    - "Political and economic correlates of pilgrimage behavior; n. d", 1981; Adams, Walter Randolph
    - "Ethnohistorical Approach to Sacred and Secular Interpretations of Traditional Pilgrimages", 1981; Adams, Walter Randolph
  - "Phonetic and Phonological Investigations in Tahltan Stress", 1998; Alderete, John
    Includes Tanya Marie Bob, "Laryngeal Phenomena in Tahltan" (MA Thesis: U.B.C., 1999)
    (F&S 4498a)
  - "Cuitlatec notes", 1973; Almstedt, Ruth
  - "Catalogue of The Marian Smith Collection in the Library of the Royal Anthropological Institute of Great Britain and Ireland", 1975; Amoss, Pamela T.
    Report (1p.); inventory of manuscript materials (20p.); inventory of photographs (5p.)
    (F&S 4599)
  - "Issues of identity for the Dakota at Santee, Nebraska, 1866-1876", Anderson, Carolyn R.
    Report (1p.)
  - "Photographs of the Skinner-Oneroad Collectionm, Heye Foundation, National Museum of the American Indian", 1995; TMsS, 3 p.; 46 35 mm slides; Anderson, Laura L.
    Photographs of Sisseton-Wahpeton materials.
  - "Wanamaker Collection of American Indian Photographs", 1980; Applegate, Susan G.
  - "Language Change in Ojibwe Dialects of Eastern Manitoba", 1997; Artuso, Christian
    Includes: Noogom gaa-izhi-anishinaabemonaaniwag: Generational Differences in Algonquin (MA thesis: University of Manitoba, 1998); 5 cassette tapes (Rec. 259)
  - "Lacandone subsistence and culinary arts", 1969; Baer, Phillip; Merrifield, William R.
  - "Abstract of recordings of Papago oral literature", 1978; Bahr, Donald M.
    (F&S 4622a)
  - "Nez Perce Kinship Terms", Baksi, Shila
  - Barbeau, Marius, Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    - "The Gwenhoot Of Alaska", 1960; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
      (F&S 3767)
    - "Temlarh'am The Land Of Plenty On The North Pacific Coast", 1960; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
      (F&S 3769)
    - "Wolf-Clan Invaders from the northern plateaux among the Tsimsyans", 1962; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
      (F&S 3770)
  - "Matlatzinca Phonology", 1967; Bartholomew, Doris
  - "Excavation Program at Montgomery Site, Chester Co., PA", 1980; Becker, Marshal J.
    Report (5p.)
    (F&S 4497)
  - "The 1918-1919 Influenza Pandemic in Berens River and Poplar River, Manitoba", 1997; Beckett, Kristen M.
  - "Recordings of Nisgha Language Field Studies/ August 1989, August 1990 Investigator: Robert Belvin", 1991; Belvin, Robert S.
  - "Contemporary Usage of the Cherokee Syllabary", 1993; Bender, Margaret
    Reading Culture: The Chreokee Syllabary and the Eastern Cherokees, 1993-1995 (Diss.: University of Chicago, 1996): transferred to Printed Materials; tape inventory (2p.); 16 cassette tapes (Rec. 262)
  - "Topic and Discourse Structure in West Greenlandic Agreement", 1996; Berge, Anna
    Report (1p.); notes on transcription (4p.); transcription of texts (185.); 3 papers: "Switch-reference of Switch-topic?," 10th Inuit Studies Conference, 1996; "Ergativity and topic in West Geenlandic," and "Discourse, topic, and switch-reference in West Greenlandic," 1998 SSILA Annual Meeting
  - "Two Hundred Years in the History of a Tlingit Indian Family", 1993, 1995; Berman, Judith
    Report (3p.)
  - "Archival research project on the Ottawa Indians of Oklahoma", 1994; Bernsten, Deborah
    Report, 1994 (1p.)
  - "The Phonetics of Interior Salish", 1991; Bessell, Nicola J.
    Report (2p.); lexical materials on "St'at'imcets elicitation" (4p.); field notebook (73p.); tape inventory (1p.); and 4 cassette tapes (Rec. 253). Includes data for Tlingit (consultants: Richard Newton, Judson Brown); Aharsaht Nuuchanulth (George Louie); Gitksan Tsimshian (Barbara Sennott); St'at'imcets (Rose Whitley) and Nxa?kepmx (Dorothy Ursaki)
    Vowel effects of uvular and pharyngeal consonants in Nxa?amxcin (Interior Salish)
  - "Searching for Stoney Point", 2001; Bisha, Tim
    Project report (2 p.), research report (10 p.), and several hundred pages of photocopies of documents from the National Archives of Canada.
  - Black, Robert A.
    - "Report on...stylistic changes...Hopi...", 1963; Black, Robert A.
    - "A Content Analysis of 81 Hopi Indian Chants" / Diss., 1964; Black, Robert A.
      (F&S 4345)
    - "Field work among the Hopi Indians..." + Cat. of Hopi tapes..., 1966; Black, Robert A.
      (F&S 4346)
  - "Ethnohistory and the Life History of a Northern Haida Woman", 1978; Blackman, Margaret B.
    Report (7p.) on biography of Florence Davidson
    (F&S 4341a)
  - "Emphatic Pronouns in Plains Cree", 1994; Blain, Eleanor M.
  - "Laryngeal Phenomena in Tahltan", 1998; Bob, Tanya
    (MS Thesis: University of British Columbia, 1999)
  - "Fieldwork at Restigouche; 1971", Bock, Philip K.
    (F&S 4527)
  - Fieldwork carried out at the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Reserve, 1969, 1970; Bonvillain, Nancy
    Report 5p.)
    (F&S 4531)
  - Mandan-Hidatsa cultural change and language studies, 1989; Bowers, Alfred W.
    Report (1p.); inventory of tapes (4p.); 11 reel to reel tapes, 7" (Rec. 84)
    (F&S 4343)
  - Boyce, Douglas W.
    - "Notes On Tuscararora Political Organization, 1650-1713", 1974; Boyce, Douglas W.
    - "The Iroquoian Tribes Of The Va. - N. C. Coastal Plain", 1974; Boyce, Douglas W.
      (F&S 4371)
    - "Tuscararora Political Organization. Ethnic Identity And Sociohistorical Demography", 1974; Boyce, Douglas W.
      (F&S 4861)
  - "Smallpox among the Indians of the Northwest Coast...", 1980; Boyd, Robert
  - "Mikasuki: grammar in outline", 1982; Boynton, Sylvia S.
  - "Struggle and Survival: Yavapai Indian History to 1910", 1996; Braatz, Timothy
    (F&S 4860)
  - Bragdon, Kathleen Joan
    - "Another Tongue Brought In: An Ethnohistorical Study of Native Writings in Massachusett", 1981; Bragdon, Kathleen Joan
    - "Misc. MSS used for dissertation research, 1981", Bragdon, Kathleen Joan
  - Brandt, Elizabeth Anne, Brandt, Elizabeth A.
    - "On the origins of linguistic stratification: The Sandia Case", 1970; Brandt, Elizabeth A.
    - "Sandia pueblo, N. Mex.: A linguistic investigation; 1970", Brandt, Elizabeth A.
      (F&S 4843)
  - "The Mourning Dove and L. V. McWhorter Correspondence", 1994; Brown, Alanna K.
    Report (2p.)
    (F&S 4842)
  - Wampanoag Text Database, 2000; Bruening, Benjamin
    Project report (2 p.); 1 CD-R
  - "The Battle of the Little Bighorn: A study in Culture, History, and the Construction of Identity", 1995; Buchholtz, Debra
    Report (1p.). Diss.(U. Minn., 2000), transferred to Printed Materials, 3/2001
  - "Problems in Southern Paiute Syntax and Semantics", 1979; Bunte, Pamela Ann
  - Linguistic status of Potawatomi in Southwest Michigan, 1995; Buszard-Welcher, Laura
    Report (18p.)
  - Pictorial survey of structure abandonment, Old Oraibi Hopi Pueblo, 1994; Cameron, Catherine M.
    Report (2p.); 52 photocopies of photographs from originals in the Southwest Museum, Huntington Library, Pasadena Public Library, and the Seaver Center, Los Angeles County Museum. Images include Hopi dwellings, dance formations, individual and group portraits.
  - Research on Passamaquoddy syntax, 1995; Campana, Mark
    Report (2p.); abstract of paper (1p.); notes on "Particle placement" (24p.); paper: "The Conjunct Order in Algonquian; one 7" reel-to-reel tape (Rec. 245)
  - Campbell, Lyle
    - "Letter to Whitfield J. Bell, Jr.; [10/19/72]", Campbell, Lyle
    - "Aztec manuscript and Xinca linguistic material. [1972, 1976]", 128; Campbell, Lyle
      (F&S 4912, 4553)
  - Study of the Language of Todos Santos (a Mayan Dialect of the Language Mam), 1968; Canger, Una
    (F&S 4481)
  - "Oklahoma post office murals painted by Native Americans, 1930s-1940s", 1995; Carlisle, John C.
    Report (1p.); 8 35mm slides Images include village scenes, councils, dancing, cooking by Native American artists Richard West, Woodrow Crumbo, Acee Blue Eagle, Stephen Mopope, Solomon McComb of Seminoles, Kiowa, Chickasaw.
  - "Spokane Linguistic Material", 1974; Carlson, Barry F.
  - "'Searching for the Bright Path': The Mississippi Choctaws from Prehistory to Removal", 1996; Carson, James Taylor
    (F&S 4801)
  - "Dakota linguistic material", 1971; Carter, Jr., Richard T.
  - "Toward a Generative Semantic Description of Onondaga", 1969; Chafe, Wallace L.
    (F&S 4715)
  - "Dine Bikeyah Bik'ah (Navajo Oil): An Ethnohistory", 1996; Chamberlain, Kathleen P.
    Report (1p.); dissertation (transferred to Printed Materials)
    (F&S 4196)
  - "The tail of the elephant: Indians in emigrant diaries, 1844-1862", 1994; Clemmer, Richard O.
    Photocopy of article, Nevada Historical Society Quarterly 30 (1987), 269-290.
  - "'Satisfied to Walk in the Ways of Their Fathers': Dakotas and Missionaries, 1835-1862", 1996; Clemmons, Linda M.
  - Collins, James
    - "Tolowa language materials; 1984", 1985; Collins, James
    - "The Structure of Tolowa, Phase II", 1988; Collins, James
  - Compton, Brian D.
    - [Upper North Wakashan and Southern Tsimshian Field Notes], 1994; Compton, Brian D.
    - "From 'smoke in the eyes' to 'smoke of the world'?: Haisla ethnomycology and the translation of the name 'Kwakiutl", 1994; Compton, Brian D.
    - "'Ghost's ears' (Exobasidium sp. affin. vaccinii) and fool's huckleberries (Menziesia ferruginea): a unique report of mycophagy on the central coast", 1994; Compton, Brian D.
    - "'It pulls everything to you': North Wakashan herbal talismans", 1994; Compton, Brian D.
    - "Upper North Wakashan and Southern Tsimshian Ethnobotany:.." Diss., 1994; Compton, Brian D.
  - "Arapaho Verbal Morphology", 2000-2001; Cowell, Andrew
    Project report (1 p.), summary of tapes and contents (25 p.)
    Related Archival Materials
    The recordings made as part of this project are cataloged under Recording Collection 278.
  - "John Honigmann's Ethnographic Work in Attawapiskat, Ontario" and "The Ethnographic Photography of John Honigmann", 1995, 1997; Cummins, Bryan
    Report, 1996 (1p.) and report, 1998 (2p.)
  - "Emergence of Academic Anthropology at the University of Pennsylvania", 1968; Darnell, Regna
  - Davies, William D.
    - "Choctaw clause structure. 1981", 1983; Davies, William D.
    - "Choctaw linguistic material", 1983; Davies, William D.
  - "Preliminary Materials for an Acoma (Kersaan Dictionary), 1969; Davis, Irvine
  - de Laguna, Frederica, De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    - "An Arctic Summer", 1930; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
      (F&S 4250)
    - "Explanation of cassette recordings made at Upernavik, West Greenland, 1979", 1985; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    - "Study of childhood memories of Greenlanders, Upernavik District, Greenland; 15 January 1991", De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Native peoples of Connecticut, 1994-1995; 2 TMssS, 3p., 10p.; Den Ouden, Amy E.
    Includes paper "Native Peoples of Connecticut: Culture, Politics and Power, 1700-1994," presented at annual meeting of the American Society for Ethnohistory, 1994.
  - "Verbs of Saying in Chilcotin Historical Narratives", 1992; Dinwoodie, David
    Report (1p.); photocopies, Sept. 1992: elicited forms, verbs of speaking, kinship terms, etc., from Lenny Solomon (36p.); transcript of narrative by Henry Solomon about a white man in the Nemiah Valley named Robertson (15p.); cassette tape (Rec. 257)
    (F&S 4438)
  - Research in Chippewa history and culture in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan, 1995; Doherty, Robert
  - Drechsel, Emmanuel J., Drechsel, Emanuel J.
    - Research on Lingua franca Creek, 1981; Drechsel, Emanuel J.
      Report (5p.) comparing Lingua franca Creek with Creek proper and Mobilian jargon
    - Research on American Indian pidgin language, 1989; Drechsel, Emanuel J.
      Report (5p.) on research in Louisiana with Coushatta (Koasati) Indians and archival resources
  - Archival research in 17th and 18th century Iroquois history, 1977; Druke, Mary A.
    Letter, Oct. 11, 1977 (2p.); Report (8p.); photocopy of English-"Nottawegh" (Mohawk)-Cherokee word list, in Duke of Northumberland's Library in hand of Cherokee Indian, John Norton (12p.)
    (F&S 4164a)
  - "Linguistic and demographic history of the Coast Tsimshian", 1970; Dunn, John A.
    Report (9p.)
    (F&S 4855)
  - "Report on Linquistic Field Work among the Pima Bajo of Eastern Sonora, Mexico", 1966; Dunnigan, Timothy
    Report on fieldwork in the highland dialect; very brief discussion concerning phonology and syntax (3p.)
    (F&S 4677)
  - "Faithful Nations and Ruthless Savages: Diplomacy and Transformation in the Arkansas River Valley, 1763 to 1828", 1999; DuVal, Karen
  - Edwards, Elizabeth A., Edwards, Elizabeth A., 1939-
    - "Topic and Topic Marking Particles in Haida", 1978; Edwards, Elizabeth A., 1939-
    - "Haida syntax material; 1983-1984", Edwards, Elizabeth A., 1939-
  - "Mountain Cahuilla Texts", 1994; Elliot, Eric; Sauvel, Katherine Siva
    Report (1p.); rough draft of Serrano-English dictionary (ca.500p.) compiled with consultant Dorothy Ramón, not alphabetized, but divided into noun and verb sections
  - "A Definite Article in Jamul Diegueño?", 1995; Epstein, Richard
    Report (1p.); 7" reel-to-reel tape (Rec. 264) of native speakers Gloria Casteneda and Helen Cuero; index and transcription of ten texts, including "Wage labor," "The Coyote and the girls," "Anastasio Cuero," "Singing at a wake," "The coyote and the two brothers," "Singing in the old days," "The book of the Indians," "The sun", "Mules and names," "Rocks"
  - Archival research on 18th century Creek agent Benjamin Hawkins, 1994; Ethridge, Robbie
  - "Research report and index for Mescalero Apache cylinder recordings, Farrer, Claire R.
  - "Introduction to an edition of J. F. Lafitau: Moers des sauvages...", 1971; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - "Navajo Adverbial Quantification of Nominals", 1996; Fernald, Theodore B.